what is love is a difficult term to define insofar as
就什么而言，爱是很难定义的术语
its application is very wide I can like jogging
它的应用范围很广，我喜欢慢跑
I can love a book a movie I can love a schnitzel I can love my
我可以爱一本书，电影，我可以爱炸肉排，我可以爱我的
women
女性
but there is a big difference between a schnitzel and my wife for example
但是例如炸肉排和我的妻子有很大的不同
is that if I value the escalope the escalope on the other hand in return it does not
就是如果我重视escalope，另一方面，escalope不会
don't value me when my wife calls me
当我老婆打电话给我时不要珍惜我
the star of his life only another desiring consciousness can
他生命中的明星只有另一种渴望的意识可以
to constitute as a desirable being that I know it and that is why we
构成一个我知道的理想存在，这就是为什么我们
can define love more precisely as the desire to be
可以更准确地将爱定义为渴望成为
longed for sweet the eternal problem of love
向往甜蜜永恒的爱情问题
how to become and how to remain desirable then the answer to this problem
如何成为和如何保持理想，那么这个问题的答案
the individual found it formerly by subjecting his life to the rules of
个人以前是通过使自己的生活服从于
community he had a specific role to play following
他在社区中扮演着特定的角色
his sex his age his social status he just had to hold him to be
他的性别，他的年龄，他的社会地位，他只需要抱着他成为
valued and loved by its entire community
受到整个社区的重视和喜爱
think of the young girl who must remain chaste before marriage
想起在结婚前必须保持贞洁的年轻女孩
think of the younger son who owes obedience to the eldest son who himself owes
想起顺服长子的小儿子
obedience to the patriarch
服从族长
only here is a phenomenon that began from the thirteenth century but above all from
唯一的现象是始于13世纪的现象，但最重要的是
the renaissance in the West which caused the greatest identity crisis
西方的文艺复兴导致了最大的身份危机
of the history of mankind this phenomenon is modernity we can
人类历史上的这种现象是现代性，我们可以
roughly summarize it by a threefold process first a process of
通过三个过程粗略地总结一下：
rationalization of scientific research which accelerates progress
科学研究合理化，加速进步
technical then a process of democratization
技术然后是民主化的过程
policy that developed the rights of the individual and finally a process of
制定个人权利的政策，并最终形成了
rationalization of economic production and liberalization of
经济生产合理化和贸易自由化
trade these three intertwined processes have
交易这三个相互交织的过程
completely destroyed all the traditional benchmarks of Western societies
彻底摧毁了西方社会的所有传统基准
the consequence for the individual is radical, the individual is now free
对个人的后果是激进的，现在个人是自由的
to value or devalue such an attitude
重视或贬低这种态度
such choices such and such an object but suddenly his person himself is confronted with this
这样的选择，这样的对象，但是突然间，他自己的人面对了这个
same freedom as for others to value it or to devalue it to say it
与他人一样自由地重视它或贬低它以说出它
otherwise my value formerly I assured it in me
否则我以前的价值我向我保证
submitting to traditional authorities now it is publicly traded on
现在提交给传统当局，它已公开交易
in the free market of individual desires
在个人欲望的自由市场中
I negotiate my value every day, hence the anguish of contemporary man
我每天都在谈判我的价值，因此当代人的痛苦
how desirable am I obsession
我的痴迷程度如何
how many people will love me and how does he respond to this anxiety
有多少人会爱我，他如何应对这种焦虑
hysterically accumulating the symbols of desirability
歇斯底里地积累着渴望的象征
this accumulation I call it with others the capital seduction it is on
我将这种积累与其他人称为资本诱惑
the capital of seduction which rests in large part in fact our society of
诱惑的资本，实际上很大程度上取决于我们的社会
consumption we say in this connection about consumption that our time and
消费，我们在这方面说关于消费，我们的时间和
materialist but it is wrong if we accumulate objects it is for
唯物主义者但是如果我们积累物体是错误的，那是错误的。
to communicate with other spirits is to make us love both
与其他灵魂交流就是让我们俩都爱
seduce
勾引
nothing less materialistic nothing more sentimental than a teenager who buys
没有什么比没有购买的少年更富有感情的了
a brand new pair of jeans that rips her knee because he wants to please
一条崭新的牛仔裤因为他想要取悦她的膝盖而撕裂
to jennifer
去珍妮佛
consumerism is not materialism
消费主义不是唯物主义
it is rather the engulfed matter sacrificed in the name of the god love or rather
而是以爱神的名义牺牲的吞噬物质，或更确切地说，
in the name of the capital seduction then from this observation on love
以资本诱惑的名义，从对爱的观察中
current how to think about the love of future years
当前如何思考对未来岁月的热爱
we can consider two hypotheses the first is to bet on a
我们可以考虑两个假设，第一个是赌一个
accentuation of this process of narcissistic capitalization what form
自恋资本化过程的强调是什么形式
will take this accentuation, it is very hard to say because it depends on
将采取这种强调，很难说，因为这取决于
a large part of social and technical innovations which are not defined
未定义的大部分社会和技术创新
difficult to predict but one can for example imagine a website of
很难预测，但是例如可以想象一个网站
encounter where a bit like with points this corn 1 we work with
遇到的地方有点像我们合作的这个玉米1
points capital seduction which varies according to my age my height to weight ratio
根据我的年龄，我的身高体重比而有所不同
diploma my salary or the number of clicks accumulated on my profile
用我的薪水或我的个人资料上累积的点击次数获得文凭
we can also imagine a chemical treatment of the breakup that
我们还可以想象对分解的化学处理
weakens the feeling of attachment there is already a program on
削弱了依恋的感觉，已经有一个程序
the mtv channel or teachers of seduction treat heartache
mtv频道或诱惑老师治疗心痛
like a disease these professors are called pick up artists so
这些教授像疾病一样被称为接载艺术家，所以
artists in French it's easy these artists and then pick-ups and lifting
用法语工作的艺术家很容易就能找到这些艺术家，然后进行接载和提举
but not just any age lifting girl so they are lifting artists
不仅是任何年龄段的提升女孩，所以他们也在提升艺术家
girl and they call they call the
女孩，他们称他们为
heartache one it is it is in English it is a suffix which means
心痛之一是用英语这是一个后缀
infections of which when it is one could translate its infections part of the unique
当它是一种感染时，可以翻译其感染的独特部分
it's not a little disgusting and in fact for the pick up artist to make a
这一点也不令人恶心，实际上，对于接送艺术家来说，
loving fixation on someone and well it's wasting time it's wasted
爱固定在某人身上，浪费时间，浪费时间
its capital of seduction and therefore we must eliminate it like a disease like a
它的诱惑资本，因此我们必须像消除疾病一样消除它
infection we can still consider a use
感染我们仍然可以考虑使用
in love with the genomic map we have it we will carry it on everyone
爱上了基因组图，我们将它带给每个人
then we would show it as a business card to check if the seduction
那么我们会将其显示为名片，以检查诱惑是否
may not lead to reproduction
可能不会导致繁殖
so of course this race for seduction like any fierce competition
因此，当然，像任何激烈的比赛一样，这场诱人的比赛
will produce two great disparities in narcissistic satisfaction and therefore
在自恋满意度上会产生两个巨大的差异，因此
also a lot of loneliness a lot of frustration
也很多寂寞很多挫败感
then we must expect that modernity itself which is at the origin
那么我们必须期望起源的现代性本身
capital seduction is called into question I am thinking in particular of reactions
资本诱惑被质疑，我正在思考特别是反应
communitarian neo-fascist or religious type but hey, such a future is
社区主义的新法西斯主义或宗教派，但嘿，这样的未来是
not inevitably another voice may be possible for
不可避免地，另一种声音可能
think about love but how to give up the hysterical demand
考虑爱情，但如何放弃歇斯底里的需求
to be valued and well by becoming aware of my nullity
通过意识到我的虚无而受到重视和很好
and yes I suck but don't worry too
是的，我很烂，但也不必担心
but if we are we are all zero it's quite easy to demonstrate
但是如果我们都是零，那很容易证明
this nullity since in order to be valued I ask the other to
这种无效性，因为为了得到重视，我要求对方
wish therefore is that I have no value in myself I have no value
因此，我希望自己没有价值我没有价值
in ourselves we all have
我们自己都有
well we all pretend to have an idol we all pretend to be an idol
好吧，我们都假装有一个偶像，我们都假装是一个偶像。
idol for someone but in fact we are all impostors and a little
某人的偶像，但实际上我们都是冒名顶替者
like the one who passes as an indifferent lord in the street when he has
就像一个无动于衷的主在街上路过时
everything planned everything calculated so that all eyes are on him so I
一切都按计划进行，所有计划都经过计算，以便所有人的目光都集中在他身上
think that becoming aware of this of this general imposture that we
认为意识到这一点，我们
concerns all those passive irene to love relationships it is because I
担心所有那些被动的爱恋关系的恋人，这是因为我
want to be adored to the tips of my nails, justified in all my choices
想要被我的指甲所崇拜，在我所有的选择中都被证明是合理的
that there is a hysteria of seduction and suddenly I want to appear perfect for
有一种歇斯底里的诱惑，突然间我想显得完美
that the other even I want it to be perfect so that it reassures me about my
另一个甚至我都希望它是完美的，这样可以使我放心
value and this results in couples obsessed with performance and who will
价值，这导致夫妻对性能的痴迷，谁会
to quit precisely at the slightest negative performance, then the opposite of this
精确地退出，至少有负面的表现，那么与此相反
attitude I invoke tenderness love as
态度，我唤起温柔的爱
what tenderness what is tenderness being time to accept
什么温柔是什么时候被接受
weaknesses of the loved one, but it is not a question of transforming into a
亲人的弱点，但这不是转变成亲人的问题。
sad couple to be caregivers 1 it's not terrible that there is on the contrary
难过的夫妻要照顾1相反，这并不可怕
a lot of charm a lot of joy in the tenderness I think in particular a type
尤其是一种类型，我在柔情中充满了很多魅力。
of humor which unfortunately very little practiced and which is a kind of poetry of
幽默，不幸的是很少实践，这是一种诗歌
clumsiness assumed I think of self-mockery for a couple who is
笨拙的假设是我想到一对夫妇的自嘲
no longer maintained supported by the constraints of tradition I think
我认为不再受到传统约束的支持
self-mockery is one of the best ways to last
自我嘲弄是持续的最佳方式之一
[Music]
[音乐]